Hello everyone,
大家好，
and I hope you enjoyed Alexander's first lecture.
我希望你们喜欢 Alexander 的第一节课。
I'm Ava,
我是 Ava ，
and in this second lecture, lecture two,
在第二节课中，
we're going to focus on this question of sequence modeling,
我们将关注序列建模的问题，
how we can build neural networks that can handle and learn from sequential data.
我们如何构建神经网络来处理和学习序列数据。
So in Alexander's first lecture,
在 Alexander 的第一节课中，
he introduced the essentials of neural networks,
他介绍了神经网络的基本原理，
starting with perceptons, building up to feed forward models
从感知器，建立前馈模型开始，
and how you can actually train these models
以及如何训练这些模型，
and start to think about deploying them forward.
并开始考虑部署它们。
Now, we're going to turn our attention to
现在我们将把注意力转向
specific types of problems that involve sequential processing of data,
涉及数据顺序处理的特定类型的问题，
and we realize why these types of problems
我们意识到为什么这些类型的问题，
require a different way of implementing and building neural networks,
需要一种不同的方式来实现和构建神经网络，
from what we've seen so far.
比起我们到目前为止所看到的。
And I think some of the components in this lecture
我认为，这节课的一些内容
traditionally can be a bit confusing or daunting at first,
一开始可能会让人感到困惑或畏惧，
but what I really, really want to do is
但我真的想要做的是，
to build this understanding up from the foundations,
从基础开始建立这种理解，
walking through step by step,
一步一步地走，
developing intuition all the way to understanding the math and the operations behind how these networks operate.
一直发展直觉到理解这些网络如何运作背后的数学和操作。
Okay, so let's get started,
好的，我们开始吧，
to, to begin, to begin,
为了开始，
I first want to motivate,
我首先想要激发，
what exactly we mean when we talk about sequential data or sequential modeling,
我们谈论序列数据或序列建模的确切含义，
so we're going to begin with a really simple, intuitive example,
所以我们将从一个非常简单、直观的例子开始，
let's say we have this picture of a ball,
假设我们有一张球的图片，
and your task is to predict where this ball is going to travel to next,
你的任务是预测这个球下一步会移动到哪里，
now, if you don't have any prior information
现在，如果你没有前置信息，
about the trajectory of the ball, its motion, its history,
关于球的轨迹，它的运动，它的历史，
any guess or prediction about its next position is going to be exactly that a random guess,
任何关于它的下一个位置的猜测或预测都是随机的猜测，
if, however, in addition to the current location of the ball,
然而，如果除了球的当前位置之外，
I gave you some information about where it was moving in the past,
我还给了你一些关于球过去移动位置的信息，
now the problem becomes much easier
现在问题变得容易多了，
and I think hopefully we can all agree,
我想希望我们都能同意，
that most likely, our most likely next prediction is that,
我们最有可能的下一个预测是，
this ball is going to move forward to the right in the next frame.
这个球将在下一帧向右移动。
So this is a really, you know, reduced down, bare bones, intuitive example,
所以这是一个非常精简的，简单的，直观的例子，
but the truth is that beyond this,
但事实是，除此之外，
sequential data is really all around us, right,
序列数据真的就在我们周围，
as I'm speaking,
就在我说话的时候，
the words coming out of my mouth form a sequence of sound waves,
从我嘴里说出来的话形成了一系列声波，
that define audio,
定义了音频，
which we can split up
我们可以分开，
to think about in this sequential manner,
以这种顺序的方式来思考，
similarly, text language can be split up into a sequence of characters or a sequence of words,
类似地，文本语言可以被分成字符序列或单词序列，
and there are many, many, many more examples
还有很多更多的例子，
in which sequential, processing sequential data is present, right,
表明序列处理，序列数据是存在的，
from medical signals, like EKGs,
从医学信号，比如心电图，
to financial markets and projecting stock prices,
到金融市场和预测股票价格，
to biological sequences encoded in DNA,
到 DNA 编码的生物序列，
to patterns in the climate,
到气候模式，
to patterns of motion and many more.
到运动模式，等等。
And so already, hopefully, you're getting a sense of what these types of questions and problems may look like
所以，希望你已经对这些类型的问题有一定的了解，
and where they are relevant in the real world.
以及它们在现实世界中的哪些方面相关。
When we consider applications of sequential modeling in the real world,
当我们考虑序列建模在现实世界中的应用时，
we can think about a number of different kind of problem definitions,
我们可以考虑一些不同类型的问题定义，
that we can have in our arsenal and work with.
我们可以在我们的武器库拥有并使用这些定义。
In the first lecture,
在第一节课中，
Alexander introduced the notions of classification and the notion of regression,
Alexander 介绍了分类和回归的概念，
where he talked about and we learned about feed forward models,
在那里他谈到了，我们学习了前馈模型，
that can operate one to one in this fixed and static setting,
它可以在这种固定和静态的设置下一对一地运行，
given the single input, predict a single output,
给定单一输入，预测单一输出，
the binary classification example,
那个二元分类的例子，
of will you succeed or pass this class,
你会不会成功通过这门课，
and here, there's no notion of sequence, there's no notion of time,
在这里，没有顺序的概念，也没有时间的概念，
Now, if we introduce this idea of a sequential component,
现在，如果我们引入这种序列分量的概念，
we can handle inputs that may be defined temporally
我们可以处理可能在时间上定义的输入，
and potentially also produce a sequential or temporal output.
并潜在地产生顺序或时间输出。
So, for as one example,
所以作为一个例子，
we can consider text language,
我们可以考虑文本语言，
and maybe we want to generate one prediction,
也许我们想要生成一个预测，
given a sequence of text,
给出一个文本序列，
classifying whether a message is a positive sentiment or a negative sentiment.
分类消息是积极的情绪还是负面的情绪。
Conversely, we could have a single input,
相反，我们可以有一个输入，
let's say an image,
比方说一幅图像，
and our goal may be now to generate text or a sequential description of this image,
现在我们的目标可能是生成该图像的文本或顺序描述，
right, given this image of a baseball player throwing a ball,
给出这张棒球运动员投球的图片，
can we build a neural network that generates that as a language caption.
我们能建立一个神经网络来生成语言字幕吗。
Finally, we can also consider applications and problems where we have sequence in, sequence out,
最后，我们还可以考虑有序列输入、序列输出的应用程序和问题，
for example, if we want to translate between two languages,
例如，如果我们想要在两种语言之间进行翻译，
and indeed this type of thinking and this type of architecture is
这种类型的想法和这种类型的架构是，
what powers the task of machine translation in your phones,
推动了你的手机中的机器翻译任务，
in Google translate and and many other examples.
在谷歌翻译和许多其他例子中。
So hopefully this has given you a picture of what sequential data looks like,
希望这能让你了解序列数据是什么样子的，
what these types of problem definitions may look like,
这些类型的问题定义可能是什么样子的，
and from this, we're going to start and build up our understanding
从这一点出发，我们将开始并建立我们的理解，
of what neural networks we can build and train for these types of problems.
我们可以建立和训练什么样的神经网络来解决这些类型的问题。
So first we're going to begin with the notion of recurrence
首先我们将从递归的概念开始，
and build up from that to define recurrent neural networks,
并从这个概念开始定义递归神经网络，
and in the last portion of the lecture,
在讲座的最后部分，
we'll talk about the underlying mechanisms, underlying the transformer architectures,
我们将讨论底层机制，底层转换器架构，
that are very, very, very powerful in terms of handling sequential data.
这些在处理序列数据方面非常、非常、非常强大。
But as I said at the beginning, right,
但正如我在开始时所说的，
the theme of this lecture is building up that understanding step by step,
这节课的主题是逐步建立这种理解，
starting with the fundamentals and the intuition.
从基础知识和直觉开始。
So to do that, we're going to go back,
要做到这一点，我们回到过去，
revisit the perceptron and move forward from there,
回顾感知器，并从那里继续前进，
right, so as Alexander introduced,
所以就像 Alexander 介绍的，
where we study the perceptron, perceptron in lecture one,
我们在第一课中研究了感知器，
the perception is defined by this single neural operation,
感知器是由这个单一的神经操作定义的，
where we have some set of inputs,
我们有一些输入，
let's say x1 to xm,
比如 x1 到 xm ，
and each of these numbers are multiplied by a corresponding weight,
这些数字中的每一个都乘以相应的权重，
passed through a non-linear activation function,
通过一个非线性激活函数，
that then generates a predicted output y hat.
然后产生一个预测的输出 ŷ 。
Here we can have multiple inputs coming in to generate our output,
在这里，我们可以有多个输入来生成我们的输出，
but still these inputs are not thought of as points in a sequence or time steps in a sequence,
但这些输入仍然不被认为是序列中的点或序列中的时间步长，
even if we scale this perceptron
即使我们扩展这个感知器，
and start to stack multiple perceptions together to define these feed forward neural networks,
并开始将多个感知器堆叠在一起来定义这些前馈神经网络，
we still don't have this notion of temporal processing or sequential information.
我们仍然没有这种时间处理或序列信息的概念。
Even though we are able to translate and convert multiple inputs,
即使我们能够翻译和转换多个输入，
apply these way operations, apply this non-linearity
应用这些方式操作，应用这种非线性，
to then define multiple predicted outputs.
然后定义多个预测输出。
So taking a look at this diagram, right,
看看这张图，
on the left in blue, you have inputs,
左边是蓝色，是输入，
on the right, in purple, you have these outputs,
右边是紫色，是输出，
and the green defines the single neural network layer,
绿色定义了单一神经网络层，
that's transforming these inputs to the outputs.
将这些输入转换为输出。
Next step, I'm going to just simplify this diagram,
下一步，我将简化这个图表，
I'm going to collapse down those stack perceptons together
我将把这些神经元叠加在一起，
and depict this with this green block,
然后用这个绿色的方块来描述，
still, it's the same operation going on, right,
仍然是同样的操作，
we have an input vector being transformed to predict this output vector.
我们有一个输入向量被变换来预测这个输出向量。
Now, what I've introduced here, which you may notice,
现在，我在这里介绍的，你们可能注意到了，
is this new variable t,
是这个新变量 t ，
which I'm using to denote a single time step,
我用它来表示单个时间步长，
we are considering an input at a single time step
我们正在考虑单个时间步长的输入，
and using our neural network to generate a single output corresponding to that input,
并使用我们的神经网络生成与该输入对应的单个输出，
how could we start to extend and build off this
我们如何开始扩展和建立它，
to now, think about multiple time steps
现在考虑多个时间步长，
and how we could potentially process a sequence of information.
以及我们如何处理一系列信息。
Well, what if we took this diagram,
那么，如果我们用这张图，
all I've done is just rotated it 90 degrees,
我所做的就是把它旋转了 90 度，
where we still have this input vector
我们仍然有这个输入向量，
and being fed in producing an output vector,
并在产生一个输出向量，
and what if we can make a copy of this network
如果我们可以复制这个网络，
and just do this operation multiple times
并多次执行这个操作，
to try to handle inputs that are fed in corresponding to different times, right.
来尝试处理对应于不同时间馈入的输入。
We have an individual time step, starting with t0,
我们有一个单独的时间步长，从 t0 开始，
and we can do the same thing, the same operation for the next time step,
我们可以做同样的事情，对下一个时间步长做同样的操作，
again treating that as an isolated instance,
再次将其视为一个孤立的实例，
and keep doing this repeatedly,
并不断地重复这样做，
and what you'll notice, hopefully, is
你会注意到，
all these models are simply copies of each other,
所有这些模型都是彼此的简单副本，
just with different inputs at each of these different time steps,
只是在每个不同的时间步长有不同的输入，
and we can make this concrete right,
我们使这一点变得具体起来，
in terms of what this functional transformation is doing,
可以根据这种功能转变所做的事情，
the predicted output at a particular time step ŷt,
在特定时间步长的预测输出 ŷt ，
is a function of the input at that time step xt,
是那个输入时间步长 xt 的函数，
and that function is what is learned and defined by our neural network weights.
而这个函数是由我们的神经网络权重学习和定义的。
Okay, so I've told you that,
好的，我已经告诉你们了，
our goal here is trying to understand sequential data, do sequential modeling,
我们的目标是试图理解序列数据，进行序列建模，
but what could be the issue with what this diagram is showing and what I've shown you here?
但是，这个图表显示的内容和我在这里显示的内容会有什么问题？
Well, yeah, go ahead.
好的，是的，继续。
Exactly, that's exactly right,
没错，这是完全正确的，
so the student's answer was that,
所以学生的回答是，
x1 could be related to x not,
x1 可能与 x 无关，
and you have this temporal dependence,
你有这种时间依赖性，
but these isolated replicas don't capture that at all,
但这些孤立的副本根本无法捕捉到这一点，
and that's exactly answers the question perfectly, right.
这就完美地回答了这个问题。
Here, a predicted output at a later time step
这里，在较后时间步长的预测输出，
could depend precisely on inputs at previous time step,
可以精确地依赖于在前时间步长的输入，
if this is truly a sequential problem with this temporal dependence.
如果这确实是具有这种时间依赖性的序列问题。
So how could we start to reason about this,
那么，我们如何开始对此进行推理，
how could we define a relation,
我们如何定义一种关系，
that links the network's computations at a particular time step
将网络在特定时间步长的计算
to prior history and memory from previous time steps.
与先前时间步长的先前历史和记忆联系起来的关系。
Well, what if we did exactly that, right,
好的，如果我们真的这么做了，
what if we simply linked the computation and the information understood by the network to these other replicas,
如果我们简单地将计算和网络理解的信息链接到其他副本，
via what we call a recurrence relation,
通过我们所说的递归关系，
what this means is that,
这意味着，
something about what the network is computing at a particular time
关于网络在特定时间计算的内容的某些信息
is passed on to those later time steps,
会传递给后面的时间步长，
and we define that according to this variable h,
我们根据这个变量 h 来定义它，
which we call this internal state,
我们称之为内部状态，
or you can think of it as a memory term,
或者你可以认为它是一个记忆项，
that's maintained by the neurons and the network,
由神经元和网络维持的，
and it's this state that's being passed time step to time step,
这种状态被一步一步地传递，
as we read in and process this sequential information,
当我们读入并处理这些序列信息时，
what this means is that the network output its predictions, its computations,
这意味着网络输出它的预测和计算，
is not only a function of the input data x,
不仅是输入数据 x 的函数，
but also we have this other variable h,
我们还有另一个变量 h ，
which captures this notion of state, captures, captures this notion of memory,
它捕获了状态，捕获了记忆，
that's being computed by the network and passed on over time.
由网络计算并随时间传递的。
Specifically, right to walk through this,
具体来说，
our predicted output ŷt depends not only on the input at a time,
我们预测的 ŷt 不仅取决于一次的输入，
but also this past memory, this past state,
还取决于这个过去的记忆，这个过去的状态，
and it is this linkage of temporal dependence and recurrence,
正是这种时间依赖性和重复性的联系，
that defines this idea of a recurrent neural unit.
定义了重复性神经单位的概念。
What I've shown is,
我所展示的是，
this, this connection that's being unrolled over time,
这种随着时间的推移而展开的联系，
but we can also depict this relationship according to a loop,
但我们也可以根据一个循环来描述这种关系，
this computation to this internal state variable h of t
对 t 的这个内部状态变量 h 的计算
is being iteratively updated over time,
随着时间的推移被迭代更新，
and that's fled back into the neurons,
然后返回到神经元中，
the neurons computation in this recurrence relation,
这个递归关系中的神经元计算，
this is how we define these recurrent cells,
这就是我们如何定义这些递归[细胞]，
that comprise recurrent neural networks or RNN,
组成递归神经网络或 RNN ，
and the key here is that we have this idea of this recurrence relation
这里的关键是我们有这个递归关系，
that captures the cyclic temporal dependency.
捕获了循环时间依赖。
And indeed, it's this idea that is
事实上，这个想法正是，
really the intuitive foundation behind recurrent neural networks or RNNs.
递归神经网络或 RNN 背后的基础。
And so let's continue to build up our understanding from here
所以，让我们从这里继续建立我们的理解，
and move forward into how we can actually define the RNN operations mathematically and in code.
并前进到我们可以如何在数学上和在代码中实际定义 RNN 操作。
So all we're going to do is formalize this relationship a little bit more,
所以我们要做的就是让这种关系更正式一点，
the key idea here is that,
这里的关键思想是，
the RNN is maintaining the state,
RNN 保持状态，
and it's updating the state at each of these time steps
它在每个时间步长更新状态，
as the sequence is processed.
随着序列的处理。
We define this by applying this recurrence relation,
我们通过应用这个递归关系来定义它，
and what the recurrence relation captures is
递归关系捕捉到的是，
how we're actually updating that internal state ht,
我们是如何更新内部状态 ht 的，
specifically, that state update is exactly like any other neural network operation that we've introduced so far,
具体地说，状态更新与我们到目前为止介绍的任何其他神经网络操作完全一样，
where again, we're learning a function defined by a set of weights w,
我们再次学习由一组权重 w 定义的函数，
we're using that function to update the cell state ht,
我们使用该函数来更新 ht 的单元状态，
and the additional component, the newness here is that,
另外一个因素，这里的新奇之处在于，
that function depends both on the input and the prior time step ht-1,
函数依赖于输入和先前的时间步长 ht-1
and what you'll know is that,
你所知道的是，
this function fw is defined by a set of weights
这个函数 fw 是由一组权重定义的，
and it's the same set of weights, the same set of parameters
它是相同的一组权重，同样的一组参数，
that are used time step to time step
随着时间的推移，
as the recurrent neural network processes this temporal information, this sequential data.
递归神经网络处理这些时间信息，这些序列数据。
Okay, so the key idea here, hopefully is coming through is that,
好的，所以这里的关键思想是，
this RNN state update operation takes this state
这个 RNN 状态更新操作接受这个状态，
and updates it each time a sequence is processed.
并在每次处理序列时更新它。
We can also translate this to
我们还可以将其转换为，
how we can think about implementing RNNs in Python code,
如何考虑在 Python 代码中实现 RNN ，
or rather pseudocode,
或者更确切地说伪代码，
hopefully getting a better understanding and intuition behind how these networks work.
有望更好地理解和直觉这些网络是如何工作的。
So what we do is,
所以我们现在要做的是，
we just start by defining an RNN,
我们从定义 RNN 开始，
for now, this is abstracted RNN,
现在这是抽象的 RNN ，
and we start, we initialize its hidden state
我们初始化它的隐藏状态，
and we have some sentence, right,
我们有一些句子，
let's say this is our input of interest,
假设这是我们感兴趣的输入，
where we're interested in predicting maybe the next word that's occurring in this sentence,
我们感兴趣的是预测这个句子中可能出现的下一个词，
what we can do is loop through these individual words in the sentence,
我们可以做的是循环遍历句子中的单词，
that define our temporal input,
定义我们时间输入，
and at each step, as we're looping through,
在每一步，当我们循环遍历时，
each word in that sentence is fed into the RNN model,
句子中的每个单词都被送到 RNN 模型中，
along with the previous hidden state,
以及先前的隐藏状态，
and this is what generates a prediction for the next word
这就是为下一个单词生成预测，
and updates the RNN state in turn.
并依次更新 RNN 状态。
Finally, our prediction for the final word in the sentence,
最后，我们对句子中最后一个单词的预测，
the word that we're missing,
我们遗漏的单词，
is simply the RNN's output,
只是 RNN 的输出，
after all the prior words have been fed in through the model.
在所有先前的单词通过模型输入后。
So this is really breaking down how the RNN works,
所以，这是分解了 RNN 是如何工作的，
how it's processing the sequential information.
它是如何处理序列信息的。
And what you've noticed is that,
你已经注意到的是，
the RNN computation includes both this update to the hidden state,
RNN 计算既包括对隐藏状态的更新，
as well as generating some predicted output at the end,
也包括在结束时生成一些预测输出，
that is our ultimate goal that we're interested in.
这是我们感兴趣的终极目标。
And so to walk through this,
让我们来了解一下，
how we're actually generating the output prediction itself,
我们是如何生成产出预测本身的，
well, the RNN computes is given some input vector,
RNN 计算得到一些输入向量，
it then performs this update to the hidden state,
然后，它对隐藏状态执行这个更新，
and this update to the hidden state is just a standard neural network operation,
这种对隐藏状态的更新只是一个标准的神经网络操作，
just like we saw in the first lecture,
就像我们在第一节课中看到的，
where it consists of taking weight matrix multiplying that by the previous hidden state,
它包括取权重矩阵乘以之前的隐藏状态，
taking another weight matrix multiplying that by the input at a time step
取另一个权重矩阵将其乘以时间步长的输入，
and applying a non-linearity,
并应用非线性，
and in this case,
在这种情况下，
because we have these two input streams,
因为我们有这两个输入流，
input data xt and the previous state h,
输入数据 xt 和先前的状态 h ，
we have these two separate weight matrices,
我们有两个单独的权重矩阵，
that the network is learning over the course of its training,
网络在其训练过程中学习，
that comes together,
这些结合在一起，
we apply the non-linearity
我们应用非线性，
and then we can generate an output at a given time step
然后我们可以在给定的时间步长生成输出，
by just modifying the hidden state,
通过修改隐藏状态，
using a separate weight matrix to update this value
使用单独的权重矩阵更新这个值，
and then generate a predicted output.
然后生成预测输出。
And that's what there is to it, right,
这就是问题所在，
that's how the RNN in its single operation
这就是 RNN 在其单个操作中
updates both the hidden state and also generates a predicted output.
更新隐藏状态并生成预测输出的方式。
Okay, so now this gives you the internal working of how the RNN computation occurs at a particular time step,
好的，现在这为你提供了 RNN 计算如何在特定时间步长发生的内部工作，
let's next think about how this looks like over time
接下来，让我们考虑一下随着时间的推移这是什么样子，
and define the computational graph of the RNN as being unrolled or expanded across across time.
并将 RNN 的计算图定义为在时间上展开或扩展。
So, so far the dominant way I've been showing the RNN is
所以，到目前为止，我所展示的 RNN 的主要方式是，
according to this loop like diagram on the left, right,
根据这个左边这个循环的图，
feeding back in on itself,
自己反馈，
another way we can visualize and think about RNN is
我们可以想象和思考 RNN 的另一种方式是，
as kind of unrolling this recurrence over time over the individual time steps in our sequence,
随着时间的推移，在各个时间步长上展开这种递归，
what this means is that,
这意味着，
we can take the network at our first time steps
我们可以在第一时间步长时获取网络，
and continue to iteratively unroll it across the time steps,
并继续迭代地在时间步长上展开它，
going on forward, all the way until we process all the time steps in our input.
向前，直到我们处理输入中的所有时间步长。
Now, we can formalize this diagram a little bit more
现在，我们可以进一步形式话这个图，
by defining the weight matrices that connect the inputs to the hidden state update,
通过定义将输入连接到隐藏状态更新的权重矩阵，
and the weight matrices that are used to update the internal state across time,
以及用于随时间更新内部状态的权重矩阵，
and finally, the weight matrices that define the update to generate a predicted output.
以及最后定义更新到生成预测输出的权重矩阵。
Now recall that,
现在回想一下，
in all these cases, right,
在所有这些情况下，
for all these three weight matrices add all these time steps,
对于所有这三个权重矩阵加上所有这些时间步长，
we are simply reusing the same weight matrices, right,
我们只是重复使用相同的权重矩阵，
so it's one set of parameters, one set of weight matrices,
所以这是一组参数，一组权重矩阵，
that just process this information sequentially.
只是按顺序处理这些信息。
Now you may be thinking,
现在你可能在想，
okay, so how do we actually start to be thinking about
好的，那么我们如何开始思考，
how to train the RNN,
如何训练 RNN ，
how to define the loss.
如何定义损失。
Given that we have this temporal processing in this temporal dependence,
假设我们在这个时间依赖中有这个时间处理，
well, a prediction at an individual time step will simply amount to a computed loss at that particular time step,
好的，在单个时间点的预测将简单地等同于在该特定时间点的计算损失，
so now we can compare those predictions time step by time step to the true label
所以，现在我们可以将这些预测逐一与真实标签进行比较，
and generate a loss value for those time steps.
并生成这些时间步长的损失值。
And finally, we can get our total loss
最后，我们可以获得全部损失，
by taking all these individual loss terms together and summing them,
通过将所有这些单独的损失项加在一起，
defining the total loss for a particular input to the RNN.
定义对 RNN 的特定输入的总损失。
If we can walk through an example
如果我们可以演示，
of how we implement this RNN in TensorFlow starting from scratch,
如何从头开始在 TensorFlow 中实现这个 RNN ，
the RNN can be defined as a layer operation and a layer class
RNN 可以定义为层操作和层类，
that Alexander introduced in the first lecture.
像 Alexander 在上节课介绍的。
And so we can define it according to an initialization of weight matrices, initialization of a hidden state,
所以我们可以根据权重矩阵的初始化，隐藏状态的初始化来定义它，
which commonly amounts to initializing these two to zero.
通常相当于将这两个初始化为零。
Next, we can define how we can actually pass forward through the RNN network
接下来，我们可以定义如何通过 RNN 网络
to process a given input X,
以处理给定的输入 X ，
and what you'll notice is,
你们会注意到，
in this forward operation,
在这个正向运算中，
the computations are exactly like we just walked through,
计算和我们刚刚看过的一样，
we first update the hidden state
我们首先更新隐藏状态，
according to that equation we introduced earlier,
根据前面介绍的方程，
and then generate a predicted output
然后生成预测输出，
that is a transformed version of that hidden state,
是隐藏状态的变换版本，
and finally, at each time step,
最后，在每个时间步长，
we return both the output and the updated hidden state,
我们返回输出和更新的隐藏状态，
as this is what is necessary to be stored to continue this RNN operation over time,
因为这是随着时间的推移继续该 RNN 操作所必需的存储，
what is very convenient is,
非常方便的是，
that although you could define your RNN network and your RNN layer completely from scratch,
尽管你可以完全从头开始定义 RNN 网络和 RNN 层，
is that TensorFlow abstracts this operation away for you,
但 TensorFlow 为你抽象了这一操作，
so you can simply define a simple RNN,
所以你可以简单地定义一个简单的 RNN ，
according to this, this call that you're seeing here,
根据你在这里看到的这个调用，
which yeah, makes all the computations very efficient and very easy,
这使得所有的计算都非常有效，非常容易，
and you'll actually get practice implementing and working with RNNs in today's software lab.
你将在今天的软件实验中练习实现和使用 RNN 。
Okay, so that gives us the understanding of RNNs
好的，这给了我们对 RNN 的理解，
and going back to what I, what I described as kind of the problem setups or the problem definitions
回到我所描述的那种问题设置或问题定义，
at the beginning of this lecture.
在这节课开始时（说的）。
I just want to remind you
我只想提醒你们，
of the types of sequence modeling problems on which we can apply RNNs right,
我们可以应用 RNN 解决序列建模问题，
we can think about taking a sequence of inputs,
我们可以考虑取一个输入序列，
producing one predicted output at the end of the sequence,
在序列的末尾产生一个预测输出，
we can think about taking a static single input
我们可以考虑采用静态的单一输入，
and trying to generate text according to according to that single input,
并尝试根据该单一输入生成文本，
and finally, we can think about taking a sequence of inputs,
最后，我们可以考虑获取一个输入序列，
producing a prediction at every time step in that sequence,
在这个序列中的每个时间步长产生一个预测，
and then doing this sequence to sequence type of prediction and translation.
然后对这个序列进行预测和翻译。
Okay, so,
好的，所以，
yeah, so, so this will be the foundation for the software lab today,
所以，这将是今天软件实验的基础，
which will focus on this problem of, of many to many processing and many to many sequential modeling,
它将专注于多对多处理和多对多序列建模的问题，
taking a sequence, going to a sequence.
取一个序列，到一个序列。
What is common and what is universal across all these types of problems and tasks
我们可能想要考虑的所有这些类型的问题和任务的共同之处和普遍之处是，
that we may want to consider with RNN is what,
我们考虑 RNN 的是，
I like to think about, what type of design criteria we need
我想我们需要什么样的设计标准，
to build a robust and reliable network for processing these sequential modeling problems.
来建立一个健壮而可靠的网络来处理这些序列建模问题。
What I mean by that is,
我的意思是，
what are the characteristics,
它们的特点是什么，
what are the design requirements that the RNN needs to fulfill
RNN 需要满足哪些设计要求，
in order to be able to handle sequential data effectively.
为了能够有效地处理序列数据。
The first is that sequences can be of different lengths, right,
第一个是序列可以有不同的长度，
they may be short, they may be long,
它们可能很短，也可能很长，
we want our RNN model or our neural network model in general
我们希望我们的 RNN 模型通用，
to be able to handle sequences of variable lengths.
能够处理可变长度的序列。
Secondly, and really importantly is,
第二，也是非常重要的一点是，
as we were discussing earlier,
正如我们之前讨论的那样，
that the whole point of thinking about things through the length of sequence is,
思考序列长度的整个关键是，
to try to track and learn dependencies in the data that are related over time,
试图跟踪和了解数据中随着时间的推移的依赖关系，
so our model really needs to be able to handle those different dependencies,
所以，我们的模型需要能够处理这些不同的依赖关系，
which may occur at times that are very, very distant from each other.
这些依赖关系可能会在彼此相隔很远发生。
Next right sequence is all about order, right,
下一个序列是关于顺序的，
there's some notion
有一些概念，
of how current inputs depend on prior inputs,
关于当前的输入依赖于先前的输入，
and the specific order of observations we see,
我们看到的观察的特定顺序，
makes a big effect on what prediction we may want to generate at the end.
对我们最终可能想要生成的预测有很大影响。
And finally, in order to be able to process this information effectively,
最后，为了能够有效地处理这些信息，
our network needs to be able to do what we call parameter sharing,
我们的网络需要能够进行我们所说的参数共享，
meaning that given one set of weights,
这意味着给定一组权重，
that set of weights should be able to apply to different time steps in the sequence
这组权重应该能够应用于序列中的不同时间步长，
and still result in a meaningful prediction.
并仍然产生有意义的预测。
And so today, we're going to focus on,
所以，今天我们将关注，
how recurrent neural networks meet these design criteria,
递归神经网络如何满足这些设计标准，
and how these design criteria motivate the need for even more powerful architectures,
以及这些设计标准如何激发对更强大的体系结构的需求，
that can outperform RNNs in sequence modeling.
在序列建模方面可以超越 RNN 。
So to understand these criteria very concretely,
因此，为了非常具体地理解这些标准，
we're going to consider a sequence modeling problem,
我们将考虑一个序列建模问题，
where given some series of words,
在给定一系列单词的情况下，
our task is just to predict the next word in that sentence,
我们的任务只是预测该句子中的下一个单词，
so let's say we have the sentence,
让我们假设我们有这句话，
this morning I took my cat for a walk,
今天早上，我带着我的猫去散步，
and our task is to predict the last word in the sentence,
我们的任务是预测句子中的最后一个单词，
given the prior words,
给出之前的单词，
This morning I took my cat for a, blank,
今天早上，我带着我的猫，空格，
our goal is to take our RNN define it
我们的目标是用我们的 RNN 来定义它，
and put it to test on this task.
在这项任务中对它进行测试。
What is our first step to doing this,
我们做这件事的第一步是什么，
well, the very, very first step,
好的，非常重要的第一步，
before we even think about defining the RNN
在我们考虑定义 RNN 之前，
is how we can actually represent this information to the network
我们如何表示这些信息给网络，
in a way that it can process and understand,
以一种它可以处理和理解的方式，
if we have a model,
如果我们有一个模型，
that is processing this data, processing this text based data,
它处理这些数据，处理这些基于文本的数据，
and wanting to generate text as output,
并希望生成文本作为输出，
our problem can arise in that,
我们的问题可能出现在，
the neural network itself is not equipped to handle language explicitly,
神经网络本身显然并不具备处理语言的能力，
remember that neural networks are simply functional operators, they're just mathematical operations,
记住，神经网络仅仅是函数运算符。它们只是数学运算，
and so we can't expect it, right,
所以我们不能期待它，
it doesn't have an understanding from the start of what a word is or what language means,
它不能从头开始理解单词是什么，或者语言是什么意思，
which means that we need a way to represent language numerically,
这意味着我们需要一种用数字表示语言的方法，
so that it can be passed in to the network to process.
这样它才能被传递到网络中进行处理。
So what we do is that,
所以我们要做的是，
we need to define a way
我们需要定义一种方法，
to translate this text, this language information, into a numerical encoding, a vector, an array of numbers,
来将文本、语言信息转换成数字编码，一个向量，一个数字数组，
that can then be fed in to our neural network
可以输入到我们的神经网络中，
and generating a vector of numbers as its output.
并生成一个数字向量作为它的输出。
So now this raises the question
因此，现在这就提出了一个问题，
of how do we actually define this transformation,
我们如何定义这种转变，
how can we transform language into this numerical encoding,
我们如何才能将语言转换成这种数字编码，
the key solution and the key way that a lot of these networks work,
关键的解决方案，也是许多这样的网络工作的关键方式，
is this notion and concept of embedding,
就是这种嵌入的概念和概念，
What that means is it's some transformation,
这意味着这需要一些转变，
that takes indices or something that can be represented as an index
使用索引或可表示为索引的东西，
into a numerical vector of a given size.
到给定大小的数值向量。
So if we think about how this idea of embedding works for language data,
所以，如果我们考虑一下嵌入的想法是如何对语言数据起作用的，
let's consider a vocabulary of words that we can possibly have in our language,
让我们来考虑一个我们的语言中可能存在的词汇，
and our goal is to be able to map these individual words in our vocabulary
我们的目标是能够将我们词汇表中的这些单独的单词
to a numerical vector of fixed size,
映射到固定大小的数字向量，
one way we could do this is
我们可以做到这一点的一种方法是，
by defining all the possible words that could occur in this vocabulary
定义这个词汇表中可能出现的所有单词，
and then indexing them,
然后对它们进行索引，
assigning an index label to each of these distinct words,
为每个不同的单词分配一个索引标签，
a corresponds to index one, cat responds to index two, so on and so forth,
a 对应于索引 1 ， cat 对应于索引 2 ，以此类推，
and this indexing maps these individual words to numbers, unique indices,
这个索引将这些单词映射到数字，唯一的索引，
what these indices can then define is what we call an embedding vector,
然后，这些所以可以定义的是我们所说的嵌入向量，
which is a fixed length encoding,
这是一种固定长度的编码，
where we've simply indicated a one value
当我们观察到该单词时，
at the index for that word when we observe that word,
我们只需在该单词的索引处表示一个值，
and this is called a one-hot embedding,
这就是所谓的 one-hot 嵌入，
where we have this fixed length vector of the size of our vocabulary,
我们有一个固定长度的词汇量向量，
and each instance of the vocabulary corresponds to a one-hot one,
词汇表的每个实例都对应着 one-hot 中的一个，
at the corresponding index.
在相应的索引处。
This is a very sparse way to do this,
这是一种非常简单的方法，
and it's simply based on purely, purely count the count index,
它只是基于纯粹的对计数索引进行计数，
there's no notion of semantic information,
这里没有语义信息的概念，
meaning that's captured in this vector based encoding.
这意味着在这种基于矢量的编码中捕捉到了语义信息。
Alternatively, what is very commonly done is
或者，通常更常见的做法是，
to actually use a neural network to learn an encoding, to learn an embedding,
使用神经网络来学习编码，来学习嵌入，
and the goal here is that, we can learn,
这里的目标是，我们可以学习，
a neural network that then captures some inherent meaning or inherent semantics in our input data
神经网络捕获我们输入数据中的一些内在含义或内在语义，
and maps related words or related inputs closer together in this embedding space,
并映射相关的单词或相关的输入在这个嵌入空间中距离更近，
meaning that they'll have numerical vectors that are more similar to each other.
这意味着它们的数值向量彼此更相似。
This concept is really, really foundational
这个概念非常重要，
to how these sequence modeling networks work and how neural networks work in general.
关于这些序列建模网络的工作方式以及神经网络的一般工作方式。
Okay, so with that in hand,
好的，有了这些，
we can go back to our design criteria,
我们可以回到我们的设计标准了，
thinking about the capabilities that we desire,
考虑到我们所需要的功能，
first we need to be able to handle variable length sequences.
首先我们需要能够处理可变长度的序列。
If we again want to predict the next word in the sequence,
如果我们再次想要预测序列中的下一个单词，
we can have short sequences, we can have long sequences,
我们可以有短序列，我们可以有长序列，
we can have even longer sentences,
我们可以有更长的句子，
and our key task is that we want to be able to track dependencies across all these different lengths.
我们的关键任务是希望能够跟踪所有这些不同长度的依赖关系。
And what we need, what we mean by dependencies is that,
我们需要的，我们所说的依赖关系是指，
there could be information very, very early on in a sequence,
在一个序列中，可能会有非常非常早的信息，
but that may not be relevant or come up late until very much later in the sequence,
但这些信息可能不相关，或者出现得很晚，直到序列中很晚的时候，
and we need to be able to track these dependencies
我们需要能够跟踪这些依赖关系，
and maintain this information in our network.
并在我们的网络中维护这些信息。
Dependencies relate to order and sequences are defined by their order,
依赖与顺序相关和序列是由顺序定义的，
and we know that same words in a completely different order have completely different meanings, right,
我们知道不同顺序的相同单词有完全不同的含义，
so our model needs to be able to handle these differences in order and the differences in length
因此，我们的模型需要能够处理这些顺序的差异和长度的差异，
that could result in different predicted outputs.
它们可能导致不同预测产出。
Okay, so hopefully that example going through the example in text
好的，希望通过文本的例子
motivates how we can think about transforming input data into a numerical encoding,
激励我们如何将输入数据转换成数字编码，
that can be passed into the RNN,
可以传递给 RNN ，
and also what are the key criteria that we want to meet in handling these types of problems.
以及我们在处理这些类型的问题时希望满足的关键标准是什么。
So, so far we've painted the picture of RNNs,
到目前为止，我们已经描绘了 RNN 的图片，
how they work, intuition their mathematical operations
它是如何工作的，直觉它们的数学运算，
and what are the key criteria that they need to meet.
以及它们需要满足的关键标准是什么。
The final piece to this is,
最后一个问题是，
how we actually train and learn the weights in the RNN.
我们如何实际训练和学习 RNN 的权重。
And that's done through back propagation algorithm
这是通过反向传播算法完成的，
with a bit of a twist to just handle sequential information,
只是处理序列信息，
if we go back and think about how we train feed forward neural network models,
如果我们回头想想我们是如何训练前馈神经网络模型的，
the steps break down in thinking through,
这些步骤在思考的过程中会被分解，
starting with an input,
从一个输入开始，
where we first take this input
我们首先从这个输入开始，
and make a forward pass through the network,
然后向前穿过网络，
going from input to output.
从输入到输出。
The key to back propagation that Alexander introduced was
Alexander 介绍的反向传播的关键是
this idea of taking the prediction and back propagating gradients back through the network,
将预测和反向传播梯度通过网络反向传播的想法，
and using this operation to then define and update the loss with respect to each of the parameters in the network
然后使用该操作来定义和更新关于网络中的每个参数的损耗，
in order to gradually adjust the parameters, the weights of the network,
以便逐渐调整网络的参数和权重，
in order to minimize the overall loss.
以便最小化总体损耗。
Now, with RNNs, as we walked through earlier,
现在，随着 RNN ，正如我们前面介绍的那样，
we have this temporal unrolling,
我们有了这个时间展开，
which means that we have these individual losses across the individual steps in our sequence,
这意味着我们在序列中的各个步骤中有这些单独的损失，
that summed together to comprise the overall loss.
这些损失加在一起构成了总体损失。
What this means is that,
这意味着，
when we do back propagation,
当我们进行反向传播时，
we have to now, instead of back propagating errors through a single network,
我们现在必须，不是通过单一的网络反向传播错误，
back propagate the loss through each of these individual time steps,
而是通过这些单独的时间步长向后传播损失，
and after we back propagate loss through each of the individual time steps,
在我们通过每个单独的时间步长反向传播损耗之后，
we then do that across all time steps,
我们然后在所有的时间步长上这样做，
all the way from our current time time t back to the beginning of the sequence.
从我们当前的时间 t 回到序列的开始。
And this is why this is why this algorithm is called back propagation through time, right,
这就是为什么这个算法被称为时间反向传播的原因，
because as you can see,
因为正如你所看到的，
the data and the predictions and the resulting errors are fed back in time
数据、预测和由此产生的误差反馈到，
all the way from where we are currently to the very beginning of the input data sequence,
从我们目前所处的位置一直反馈到输入数据序列的最开始，
so the back propagation through time is actually a very tricky algorithm to implement in practice,
穿越时间的反向传播是一个在实践中很难实现的算法，
and the reason for this is,
这样的原因是，
if we take a close look,
如果我们仔细观察，
looking at how gradients flow across the RNN,
梯度是如何在 RNN 上流动的，
what this algorithm involves is many, many repeated computations and multiplications of these weight matrices
这个算法涉及到的是这些权重矩阵多次重复计算和乘法，
repeatedly against each other,
相互重复，
in order to compute the gradient with respect to the very first time step,
为了计算相对于第一个时间步长的梯度，
we have to make many of these multiplicative repeats of the weight matrix.
我们必须对权重矩阵进行多次乘法重复。
Why might this be problematic,
这为什么会有问题，
well, if this weight matrix w is very, very big,
好的，如果这个权重矩阵 w 非常大，
what this can result in is what they call, what we call the exploding gradient problem,
这可能导致他们所说的爆炸性梯度问题，
where our gradients that we're trying to use to optimize our network do exactly that,
我们试图用来优化网络的梯度就是这样做的，
they blow up, they explode,
它们爆炸了，
and they get really big
它们变得非常大，
and makes it infeasible and not possible to train the network stably,
使得稳定地训练网络变得不可行和不可能，
what we do to mitigate this is a pretty simple solution called gradient clipping,
我们所做的是一个非常简单的解决方案，称为梯度裁剪，
which effectively scales back these very big gradients to try to constrain them,
它有效地缩小了这些非常大的梯度，约束它们，
more, in a more restricted way.
以更受限制的方式。
Conversely, we can have the instance where the weight matrices are very, very small,
相反，我们可以有这样的例子，其中权重矩阵非常非常小，
and if these weight matrices are very, very small,
如果这些权重矩阵非常非常小，
we end up with a very, very small value at the end
我们最终得到一个非常非常小的值，
as a result of these repeated weight matrix computations and these repeated multiplications,
因为这些重复的权重矩阵计算和重复乘法的结果，
and this is a very real problem in RNN in particular,
这是一个非常真实的问题，特别是在 RNN 中，
where we can lead into this [funnel] called a vanishing gradient,
我们可以引入一个叫做梯度消失的[漏斗]，
where now your gradient has just dropped down close to zero,
现在你的梯度已经下降到接近于零，
and again, you can't train the network stably.
再次，你不能稳定地训练网络。
Now, there are particular tools that we can use to implement,
现在，我们可以使用一些特定的工具来实现，
that we can implement to try to mitigate the vanishing gradient problem,
我们可以实现来尝试缓解梯度消失的问题，
and we'll touch on each of these three solutions briefly.
我们将简要介绍这三个解决方案。
First being, how we can define the activation function in our network
首先，我们如何定义我们网络中的激活函数，
and how we can change the network architecture itself
以及我们如何改变网络体系结构本身，
to try to better handle this vanishing gradient problem.
以更好地处理这个梯度消失问题。
Before we do that,
在我们这么做之前，
I want to take just one step back
我只想退后一步，
to give you a little more intuition about why vanishing gradients can be a real issue for recurrent neural networks.
让你们更直观地了解为什么递归神经网络的真正问题是梯度消失。
Point I've kept trying to reiterate,
我一直试图重申的一点是，
is this notion of dependency in the sequential data
序列数据中的依赖关系的概念，
and what it means to track those dependencies,
以及跟踪这些依赖关系的意义，
well, if the dependencies are very constrained in a small space,
如果依赖关系被限制在一个很小的空间内，
not separated out that much by time,
而不是通过时间来分离，
this repeated gradient computation and the repeated weight matrix multiplication is not so much of a problem.
那么重复的梯度计算和重复的权重矩阵乘法就不是什么问题了。
If we have a very short sequence,
如果我们有一个非常短的序列，
where the words are very closely related to each other,
其中单词之间的联系非常紧密，
and it's pretty obvious what our next output is going to be.
很明显，我们的下一个产出会是什么。
The rnn can use the immediately passed information to make a prediction,
RNN 可以使用立即传递的信息来进行预测，
and so there are not going to be that many, that much of a requirement to learn effective weights,
因此，学习有效权重的要求就不会那么多，
if the related information is close to each other temporally.
如果相关信息在时间上彼此接近。
Conversely, now if we have a sentence where we have a more long term dependency,
相反，现在如果我们有一个句子，有一个更长的依赖，
what this means is that we need information from way further back in the sequence
这意味着，我们需要来自序列中更靠前的信息，
to make our prediction at the end,
才能在最后做出预测，
and that gap between what's relevant and where we are at currently becomes exceedingly large,
相关信息和我们目前所处位置之间的差距变得非常大，
and therefore the vanishing gradient problem is increasingly exacerbated,
因此，梯度消失的问题日益加剧，
meaning that we really need to,
意味着我们需要，
the RNN becomes unable to connect the dots and establish this long term dependency,
RNN 变得无法连接这些点并建立这种长期依赖，
all because of this vanishing gradient issue.
这一切都是因为这种梯度消失的问题。
So the ways that we can input,
因此，我们可以输入的方法，
the ways and modifications that we can make to our network
我们可以对我们的网络进行的修改，
to try to alleviate this problem threefold.
试图从三个方面缓解这个问题。
The first is that we can simply change the activation functions in each of our neural network layers
首先，我们可以简单地更改每个神经网络层中的激活函数，
to be such that they can effectively try to mitigate and safeguard from gradients in instances,
以便它们可以有效地尝试缓解和保护在以下情况下的梯度，
where from shrinking the gradients in instances where the data is greater than zero,
在数据大于零的情况下收缩梯度，
and this is in particular true for the ReLU activation function,
对于 ReLU 激活函数来说尤其如此，
and the reason is that in all instances where x is greater than zero,
原因是在 x 大于零的所有情况下，
with the ReLU function, the derivative is one,
对于 ReLU 函数，导数是 1 ，
and so that is not less than one
所以这不小于 1 ，
and therefore it helps in mitigating the vanishing gradient problem.
因此它有助于缓解渐变消失问题。
Another trick is how we initialize the parameters in the network themselves
另一个诀窍是我们如何初始化网络本身的参数，
to prevent them from shrinking to zero too rapidly,
以防止它们太快地缩小到零，
and there are, there are mathematical ways that we can do this,
有一些数学方法可以做到这一点，
namely by initializing our weights to identity matrices,
也就是把我们的权重初始化为单位矩阵，
and this effectively helps in practice to prevent the weight updates to shrink too rapidly to zero.
这在实践中有效地帮助防止权重更新过快地收缩到零。
However, the most robust solution to the vanishing gradient problem is
然而，对消失梯度问题最稳健的解决方案是
by introducing a slightly more complicated version of the recurrent neural unit
通过引入稍微复杂一点的递归神经单元，
to be able to more effectively track and handle long term dependencies in the data,
来能够更有效地跟踪和处理数据中的长期依赖关系，
and this is this idea of [dating],
这就是[]的想法，
and what the idea is,
这个想法是，
is by controlling selectively the flow of information into the neural unit
通过有选择地控制流入神经单元的信息流，
to be able to filter out what's not important while maintaining what is important,
以便能够过滤掉不重要的东西，同时保持重要的东西，
and the key and the most popular type of recurrent unit that achieves this gated computation is
实现这种门控计算的关键和最受欢迎的递归单元类型被称为
called the LSTM, or long short term memory network,
LSTM ，或长期短期记忆网络，
today we're not going to go into detail on LSTMs,
今天，我们不打算详细讨论 LSTM ，
their mathematical details, their operations and so on,
它们的数学细节、它们的操作等等，
but I just want to convey the key idea and intuitive idea
但我只想传达有效的关键思想和直观思想，
about why these LSTMs are effective at tracking long term dependencies.
关于为什么这些 LSTM 在跟踪长期依赖项方面是有效的。
The core is that,
核心是，
the lstm is able to control the flow of information through these gates
LSTM 能够控制通过这些门的信息流，
to be able to more effectively filter out the unimportant things
从而能够更有效地过滤掉不重要的东西，
and store the important things,
存储重要的东西，
what you can do is,
你可以做的是，
implement, implement LSTM in TensorFlow, just as you would in RNN,
在 TensorFlow 中实现 LSTM ，就像 RNN 一样，
but the core concept that I want you to take away when thinking about the LSTM is
但我希望你们在考虑 LSTM 时的核心概念是，
this idea of controlled information flow through gates,
这个受控信息流通过门的想法，
very briefly, the way that LSTM operates is
简而言之， LSTM 的操作方式是，
by maintaining a cell state just like a standard RNN,
通过控制像标准 RNN 一样的单元状态，
and that cell state is independent from what is directly outputted,
并且单元状态独立于直接输出的内容，
the way the cell state is updated is according to these gates that control the flow of information,
单元状态更新的方式是根据这些控制信息流的门，
forgetting and eliminating what is irrelevant, storing the information that is relevant,
忘记和消除不相关的东西，存储相关的信息，
updating the cell state in turn,
依次更新单元状态，
and then filtering this updated cell state to produce the predicted output,
然后对更新后的单元状态进行滤波以产生预测输出，
just like the standard RNN.
就像标准的 RNN 一样。
And again, we can train the LSTM using the back propagation through time algorithm,
再次，我们可以使用时间反向传播算法来训练 LSTM ，
but the mathematics of how the L S T M is defined allows for a completely uninterrupted flow of the gradients,
但 LSTM 如何定义的数学允许完全不间断的梯度流动，
which completely eliminates the largely eliminates the vanishing gradient problem that I introduced earlier.
这在很大程度上消除了我前面介绍的梯度消失问题。
Again, we're not,
再次，我们不是，
if you're if you're interested in learning more about the mathematics and the details of LSTMs,
如果你有兴趣学习更多关于 LSTM 的数学知识和细节，
please come and discuss with us after the lectures,
请在讲座结束后与我们讨论，
but again, just emphasizing the core concept and the intuition behind how the LSTM operates.
但再次强调 LSTM 运作背后的核心概念和直觉。
Okay, so, so far where we've at, where we've been at,
好的，所以，到目前为止，
we've covered a lot of ground,
我们已经覆盖了很多领域，
we've gone through the fundamental workings of RNN,
我们已经了解了 RNN 的基本工作原理，
the architecture, the training, the type of problems that they've been applied to.
架构、训练以及它们所应用的问题类型。
And I'd like to close this part by considering some concrete examples
我想通过考虑一些具体的例子来结束这一部分，
of how you're going to use RNNs in your software lab.
这些例子说明如何在软件实验中使用 RNN 。
And that is going to be in the task of music generation,
这将是音乐生成的任务，
where you're going to work to build an RNN,
你将致力于建立一个 RNN ，
that can predict the next musical note in a sequence
它可以预测序列中的下一个音符，
and use it to generate brand new musical sequences that have never been realized before.
并用它来生成以前从未实现过的全新音乐序列。
So to give you an example
所以给你们举个例子，
of just the quality and and type of output that you can try to aim towards,
说明你们可以尝试瞄准的输出的质量和类型，
a few years ago, there was a work that trained in RNN on a corpus of classical music data
几年前，有一部作品在 RNN 上接受了古典音乐数据语料库的训练，
and famously there's this composer, Schubert,
著名的作曲家 Schubert ，
who wrote a famous unfinished symphony,
写了一首著名的未完成的交响曲，
that consisted of two movements,
由两个乐章组成，
but he was unable to finish his his symphony before he died,
但他无法在去世前完成他的交响乐，
so he died and then he left the third movement unfinished,
他去世了，然后留下了未完成的第三乐章，
so a few years ago, a group trained an RNN based model
几年前，一个小组训练了一个基于 RNN 的模型，
to actually try to generate the third movement to schubert's famous unfinished symphony,
试图生成 Schubert 著名的未完成交响乐的第三乐章，
given the prior two movements,
给定之前的两个乐章，
so I'm going to play the result quite right now.
所以我现在就来播放结果。
I paused, I interrupted it quite abruptly there,
我暂停一下，我在那里突然地打断了它，
but if there are any classical music aficionados out there,
但如果有任何古典音乐爱好者，
hopefully you get an appreciation for kind of the quality that was generated in terms of the music quality,
希望你能欣赏到音乐质量方面产生的某种质量，
and this was already from a few years ago,
而这已经是几年前的事了，
and as we'll see in the next lectures
正如我们将在接下来的课程中看到的，
and continuing with this theme of generative AI,
并继续这个生成性人工智能的主题，
the power of these algorithms has advanced tremendously,
这些算法的能力已经取得了进步，
since we first played this example,
自从我们第一次播放这个例子以来，
particularly in, you know, a whole range of domains which I'm excited to talk about,
特别是在，我很兴奋地谈到了一系列领域，
but not for now.
但目前还不是时候。
Okay, so you'll tackle this problem head on in today's lab RNN music generation.
好的，你将在今天的实验 RNN 音乐生成中正面解决这个问题。
Also, we can think about the simple example of input sequence to a single output with sentiment classification,
此外，我们还可以考虑将输入序列转换为具有情感分类的单个输出的简单示例，
where we can think about, for example, text like tweets
例如，我们可以考虑像推特这样的文本，
and assigning positive or negative labels to these,
并为这些文本赋予积极或消极的标签，
these text examples based on the content that is learned by the network.
这些文本例子基于网络学习的内容。
Okay, so this kind of concludes the portion on RNNs,
好的，关于 RNN 的部分已经结束了，
and I think it's quite remarkable,
我认为这是相当了不起的，
that using all the foundational concepts and operations, that we've talked about so far,
使用我们到目前为止讨论的所有基本概念和操作，
we've been able to try to build up networks that handle this complex problem of sequential modeling.
我们能够尝试建立网络来处理这个复杂的序列建模问题。
But like any technology, right,
但就像任何技术一样，
and RNN is not without limitations,
RNN 也不是没有局限性的，
so what are some of those limitations
那么，这些限制有哪些，
and what are some potential issues that can arise with using RNNs or even LSTMs.
使用 RNN 甚至 LSTM 可能会出现哪些潜在问题。
The first is this idea of encoding and depend and dependency,
第一种是编码和依赖的思想，
in terms of the temporal separation of data that we're trying to process,
就我们试图处理的数据的时间分离而言，
while RNN require is that the sequential information is fed in and processed time step by time step,
RNN 要求对时序信息进行逐次馈入和时间处理，
what that imposes is what we call an encoding bottleneck, right,
这造成了我们所说的编码瓶颈，
where we're trying to encode a lot of content,
我们试图编码大量内容的地方，
for example, a very large body of text,
例如，将非常大的文本主体，
many different words into a single output,
许多不同的单词到单个输出中，
that may be just at the very last time step,
这可能只是最后一个时间点，
how do we ensure that all that information leading up to that time step
我们如何确保该时间点之前的所有信息
was properly maintained and encoded and learned by the network,
都得到了适当的维护、编码和网络学习，
in practice, this is very, very challenging
在实践中，这是非常具有挑战性的，
and a lot of information can be lost.
很多信息可能会丢失。
Another limitation is that,
另一个限制是，
by doing this time step by time step processing,
通过逐个时间地进行这种时间步进处理，
RNNs can be quite slow,
RNN 可能相当慢，
there is not really an easy way to parallelize that computation.
没有一种真正简单的方法来并行化这种计算。
And finally, together, these components of the encoding bottleneck,
最后，编码瓶颈的这些组件加在一起，
the requirement to process this data step by step, imposes the biggest problem,
要求逐步处理这些数据，造成了最大的问题，
which is when we talk about long memory,
这就是当我们谈论长记忆时，
the capacity of the RNN and the LSTM is really not that long,
RNN 和 LSTM 的容量确实没有那么长，
we can't really handle data of tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands,
我们真的无法处理数万或数十万的数据，
or even beyond sequential information that effectively to learn
甚至超出了有效学习的序列信息，
the complete amount of information and patterns,
完整信息量和模式，
that are present within such a rich data source.
出现在如此大的数据源。
And so because of this,
正因为如此，
very recently, there's been a lot of attention,
最近，人们非常关注，
in how we can move beyond this notion of step by step, recurrent processing,
我们如何超越这种循序渐进的循环处理的概念，
to build even more powerful architectures for processing sequential data.
建立更强大的架构来处理顺序数据。
To understand how we do, how we can start to do this,
为了理解我们是如何做的，我们如何开始做这件事，
let's take a big step back, right,
让我们后退一大步，
think about the high level goal of sequence modeling that I introduced at the very beginning.
想想我在一开始介绍的序列建模的高级目标。
Given some input, a sequence of data,
给定一些输入，一个数据序列，
we want to build a feature encoding,
我们想要构建一个特征编码，
and use our neural network to learn that
并使用我们的神经网络来学习，
and then transform that feature encoding into a predicted output.
然后将特征编码转换为预测输出。
What we saw is that,
我们看到的是，
RNNs used this notion of recurrence to maintain order information,
RNN 使用这种递归的概念来维护顺序信息，
processing information time step by time step,
一步一步地处理信息，
but as I just mentioned,
但正如我刚才提到的，
we had these key three bottlenecks to RNN,
我们面临着这三个关键的瓶颈，
what we really want to achieve is
我们真正想要实现的是，
to go beyond these bottlenecks and achieve even higher capabilities in terms of the power of these models,
超越这些瓶颈，在这些模型的能力方面实现更高的能力，
rather than having an encoding bottleneck,
不是存在编码瓶颈，
ideally we want to process information continuously as a continuous stream of information,
理想情况下，我们希望将信息作为连续的信息流持续处理，
rather than being slow,
不是变慢，
we want to be able to parallelize computations to speed up processing,
我们希望能够并行化计算以加快处理速度，
and finally, of course, our main goal is to really try to establish long memory,
最后，当然，我们的主要目标是真正尝试建立长期记忆，
that can build a nuanced and rich understanding of sequential data.
以建立对顺序数据的细微差别和丰富的理解。
The limitation of RNN,
RNN 的局限性，
that's linked to all these problems and issues in our inability to achieve these capabilities is that,
与我们无法实现这些能力的所有这些问题和问题联系在一起的是，
they require this time step by time step processing,
它们需要时间一步一步地处理，
so what if we could move beyond that,
那么，如果我们可以超越这一点，又会怎样，
what if we could eliminate this need for recurrence entirely
如果我们可以完全消除这种重复的需要，
and not have to process the data time step by time.
并且不必逐个时间地处理数据。
Well, a first and naive approach would be,
那么，第一个也是天真的方法是，
to just squash all the data, all all, all the time steps together
把所有的数据，所有的步骤放在一起，
to create a vector that's effectively concatenated, right,
创建一个有效连接的向量，
the time steps are eliminated, there just one one stream,
时间步长被消除了，只有一个流，
where we have now one vector input with the data from all time points,
我们有一个包含所有时间点数据的矢量输入，
that's then fed into the model,
然后将其输入到模型中，
it calculates some feature vector
它计算一些特征向量，
and then generates some output,
然后生成一些输出，
which hopefully makes sense,
希望这是有意义的，
and because we've squashed all these time steps together,
因为我们一起挤压了所有这些时间步长，
we could simply think about maybe building a feed forward network,
我们可以简单地考虑建立一个前馈网络，
that could, that could do this computation,
可以进行这种计算，
well, with that, we eliminate the need for recurrence,
有了这一点，我们就消除了递归的必要性，
but we still have the issues that,
但我们仍然有这样的问题，
it's not scalable,
它是不可扩展的，
because the dense feed forward network would have to be immensely large,
因为密集的前馈网络必须非常大，
defined by many, many different connections,
由许多不同的连接定义，
and critically, we've completely lost our in order information
更重要的是，我们已经完全失去了我们的有序信息，
by just squashing everything together blindly,
因为我们只是盲目地将所有东西挤压在一起，
there's no temporal dependence,
没有时间依赖性，
and we're then stuck in our ability to try to establish long term memory.
我们就会被困在试图建立长期记忆的能力中。
So what if instead we could still think about bringing these time steps together,
那么，如果我们仍然可以考虑将这些时间步长集中在一起，
but be a bit more clever about how we try to extract information from this input data,
但在如何尝试从这些输入数据中提取信息时更聪明一点，
the key idea is this idea of being able to identify and attend to
关键的想法是能够识别和关注，
what is important in a potentially sequential stream of information,
潜在顺序信息流中的重要内容，
and this is the notion of attention or self attention,
这就是注意力或自我注意力的概念，
which is an extremely, extremely powerful concept in modern deep learning and AI,
在现代深度学习和人工智能中，这是一个非常、非常强大的概念，
I cannot understate or I don't know, understate, overstate,
我不能轻描淡写，或者，夸大，
I cannot emphasize enough how powerful this concept is,
这个概念有多么强大，我怎么强调都不为过，
attention is the foundational mechanism of the transformer architecture,
注意力是转换器体系结构的基本机制，
which many of you may have heard about,
你们中的许多人可能已经听说过，
and it's, the notion of a transformer can often be very daunting,
转换器的概念通常会非常令人生畏，
because sometimes they're presented with these really complex diagrams
因为有时它们是用这些非常复杂的图表呈现的，
or deployed in complex applications,
或者部署在复杂的应用程序中，
and you may think,
你可能会想，
okay, how do I even start to make sense of this,
好的，我怎么才能理解这一点，
at its core, though,
不过，在它的核心，
attention, the key operation is a very intuitive idea,
注意力，关键操作是一个非常直观的想法，
and we're going to, in the last portion of this lecture,
在这节课的最后一部分，
break it down step by step,
我们将一步一步地分析它，
to see why it's so powerful
看看为什么它如此强大，
and how we can use it as part of a larger neural network, like a transformer.
以及我们如何将它用作更大的神经网络的一部分，比如转换器。
Specifically, we're going to be talking and focusing on this idea of self attention,
具体地说，我们将讨论并关注这种自我注意力的概念，
attending to the most important parts of an input example,
注意输入示例中最重要的部分，
so let's consider an image,
那么让我们来考虑一张图片，
I think it's most intuitive to consider an image, first,
我认为首先考虑一幅图像是最直观的，
this is a picture of iron man,
这是一张钢铁侠的照片，
and if our goal is to try to extract information from this image of what's important,
如果我们的目标是试图从这张图像中提取重要的信息，
what we could do maybe is using our eyes naively scan over this image,
我们可以做的也许是用我们的眼睛天真地扫描这张图像，
pixel by pixel, right, just going across the image,
逐个像素，只是浏览图像，
however, our brains maybe, maybe internally they're doing some type of computation like this,
然而，我们的大脑可能在内部进行某种类型的计算，
but you and I, we can simply look at this image
但你和我，我们可以简单地看着这张图像，
and be able to attend to the important parts,
并能够关注重要的部分，
we can see that it's iron man coming at you right in the image
我们可以看到钢铁侠在图像中向你走来，
and then we can focus in a little further and say,
然后我们可以更进一步地关注，
okay, what are the details about iron man that may be important,
好的，关于钢铁侠的哪些细节可能是重要的，
what is key,
什么是关键，
what you're doing is,
你所做的是，
your brain is identifying which parts are attending to, to attend to,
你的大脑正在识别哪些部分正在关注，
and then extracting those features that deserve the highest attention,
然后提取那些值得最高关注的特征，
the first part of this problem is really the most interesting and challenging one,
这个问题的第一部分确实是最有趣和最具挑战性的，
and it's very similar to the concept of search,
它与搜索的概念非常相似，
effectively, that's what search is doing,
实际上，这就是搜索做的事情，
taking some larger body of information
获取一些更大的信息主体，
and trying to extract and identify the important parts.
并试图提取和识别重要的部分。
So let's go there next, how does search work,
所以，我们我们去那里，搜索是如何工作的，
you're thinking you're in this class,
你认为你是这个班的学生，
how can I learn more about neural networks,
我如何才能了解更多关于神经网络的知识，
well, in this day and age,
嗯，在这个时代，
one thing you may do besides coming here and joining us
除了来到这里加入我们之外，
is going to the Internet,
你可能会做的一件事就是上网，
having all the videos out there,
把所有的视频都放在网上，
trying to find something that matches,
试图找到匹配的东西，
doing a search operation,
进行搜索操作，
so you have a giant database, like YouTube,
所以你有一个巨型数据库，比如 YouTube ，
you want to find a video,
你想找到一段视频，
you enter in your query, deep learning,
你输入你的问题，深度学习，
and what comes out are some possible outputs, right,
结果是一些可能的结果，
for every video in the database,
对于数据库中的每个视频，
there is going to be some key information related to that to that video,
都会有一些与该视频相关的关键信息，
let's say the title,
比如标题，
now to do the search,
现在要进行搜索，
what the task is to find the overlaps between your query and each of these titles, right,
任务是找到你的查询和这些标题之间的重叠部分，
the keys in the database,
数据库中的键，
what we want to compute is a metric of similarity and relevance between the query and these keys,
我们要计算的是查询和这些键之间的相似性和相关性的度量，
how similar are they to our desired query,
它们与我们所需的查询有多相似，
and we can do this step by step,
我们可以一步一步地做到这一点，
let's say this first option of a video about the elegant giant sea turtles,
让我们来看一段关于优雅的巨型海龟的视频的第一个选项，
not that similar to our query about deep learning,
与我们对深度学习的查询不太相似，
our second option, introduction to deep learning,
我们的第二个选项，深度学习入门，
the first introductory lecture on this class,
这节课的第一节入门课，
yes, highly relevant,
是的，非常相关，
The third option, a video about the late and great Kobe Bryant,
第三个选项，一段关于已故伟大的科比的视频，
not that relevant,
并不是很相关，
the key operation here is that,
这里的关键操作是，
there is this similarity computation bringing the query and the key together,
进行相似性计算，将查询和关键字结合在一起，
the final step is
最后一步是，
now that we've identified what key is relevant,
我们已经确定了哪些关键是相关的，
extracting the relevant information,
提取相关信息，
what we want to pay attention to, and that's the video itself,
我们想要关注的是什么，那就是视频本身，
we call this the value,
我们称这为值，
and because the search is implemented well,
因为搜索执行得很好，
we've successfully identified the relevant video on deep learning,
我们已经成功地确定了深度学习相关的视频，
that you are going to want to pay attention to.
你将想要关注的。
And it's this, this idea, this intuition
正是这种，这种想法，这种直觉，
of giving a query, trying to find similarity,
提出一个问题，试图找到相似之处，
trying to extract the related values,
试图提取相关的值，
that form the basis of self attention,
形成自我注意力的基础，
and how it works in neural networks, like transformers.
以及它如何在神经网络中工作，比如转换器。
So to go concretely into this, right,
所以具体来说，
let's go back now to our text, our language example,
让我们回到我们的文本，我们的语言例子，
with the sentence,
对于句子，
our goal is to identify and attend to features in this input
我们的目标是识别和注意输入中的特征，
that are relevant to the semantic meaning of the sentence.
与句子语义相关的。
Now, first step, we have sequence, we have order,
现在，第一步，我们有顺序，
we've eliminated recurrence, right,
我们已经消除了递归，
we're feeding in all the time steps all at once,
我们把所有的时间步长都输入进去，
we still need a way to encode and capture this information about order and this positional dependence,
我们仍然需要一种方法来编码和捕获关于顺序和位置依赖的信息，
how this is done, is this idea of positional encoding,
如何做到这一点，是位置编码的想法，
which captures some inherent order information present in the sequence,
它捕获了序列中存在的一些固有顺序信息，
I'm just going to touch on this very briefly,
我只想简单地谈一下这一点，
but the idea is related to this idea of embeddings, which I introduced earlier,
但这个想法与我之前介绍过的嵌入的想法有关，
what is done is a neural network layer is used to encode positional information,
所做的是使用神经网络层来编码位置信息，
that captures the relative relationships in terms of order within, within this text,
位置信息根据本文中的顺序捕获相对关系，
that the high level concept, right,
这是高层次的概念，
we're still being able to process these time steps all at once,
我们仍然能够一次处理所有这些时间步长，
there is no notion of time, step or other, the data is singular,
没有时间、步骤或其他的概念，数据是单一的，
but still we learn this encoding that captures the positional order information,
但我们仍然了解到这种捕获位置顺序信息的编码，
now our next step is to take this encoding
现在，我们的下一步是采用这种编码，
and figure out what to attend to,
并找出要注意的内容，
exactly like that search operation that I introduced with the YouTube example,
就像我在 YouTube 示例中介绍的搜索操作一样，
extracting a query, extracting a key, extracting a value and relating them to each other.
提取查询，提取关键字，提取值，并将它们彼此关联。
So we use neural network layers to do exactly this,
因此，我们使用神经网络层来实现这一点，
given this positional encoding,
对于这种位置编码，
what attention does is applies a neural network layer,
需要注意的是应用一个神经网络层，
transforming that, first generating the query,
对其进行转换，首先生成查询，
we do this again using a separate neural network layer
我们使用单独的神经网络层再次这样做，
and this is a different set of weights, a different set of parameters,
这是一组不同的权重，一组不同的参数，
that then transform that positional embedding in a different way,
然后以不同的方式转换位置嵌入，
generating a second output, the key,
生成第二个输出，即关键字，
and finally, this operation is repeated with a third layer,
最后，对第三层重复该操作，
a third set of weights generating the value.
第三组权重生成值。
Now, with these three in hand, the key, the query, the key and the value,
现在，有了这三个，查询、关键字和值，
we can compare them to each other,
我们可以将它们相互比较，
to try to figure out,
试图找出，
where in that self input the network should attend to what is important,
网络应该在自我输入中关注什么是重要的，
and that's the key idea behind this similarity metric,
这就是这个相似性度量背后的关键思想，
or what you can think of as an attention score,
或者说你可以认为是注意力得分，
what we're doing is,
我们所做的是，
we're computing a similarity score between a query and the key,
我们计算查询和键之间的相似性分数，
and remember that these query and key values are just arrays of numbers,
记住，这些查询值和键值只是数字的数组，
we can define them as arrays of numbers,
我们可以将它们定义为数字数组，
which you can think of as vectors in space,
你可以将其视为空间中的向量，
the query, the query values are some vector,
查询值是一些向量，
the key, the key values are some other vector,
键值是其他一些向量，
and mathematically, the way that we can compare these two vectors
在数学上，我们可以比较这两个向量，
to understand how similar they are
以了解它们有多相似，
is by taking the dot product and scaling it,
是通过点积和比例来实现的，
captures how similar these vectors are,
捕捉到这些向量有多相似，
how whether or not they're pointing in the same direction, right,
它们是否指向同一个方向，
this is the similarity metric,
这是相似性度量，
and if you are familiar with a little bit of linear algebra,
如果你熟悉一点线性代数，
this is also known as the cosine similarity,
这也被称为余弦相似性，
the operation functions exactly the same way for matrices,
这个运算对矩阵的作用与此完全相同，
if we apply this dot product operation to our query in key matrices, key matrices,
如果我们将这个点积运算应用于查询和键矩阵，
we get this similarity metric out.
我们就得到了这个相似性度量。
Now, this is very, very key in defining our next step,
现在，在定义我们的下一步时，这是非常非常关键的，
computing the attention weighting
计算注意力权重，
in terms of what the network should actually attend to within this input,
根据网络在这一输入中应该实际关注的内容，
this operation gives us a score,
这个操作给了我们一个分数，
which defines how, how the components of the input data are related to each other,
定义输入数据的组件如何相互关联，
so, given a sentence, right,
因此，给出一个句子，
when we compute this similarity score metric,
当我们计算这个相似性得分度量时，
we can then begin to think of weights,
我们就可以开始考虑权重，
that define the relationship between the sequential, the components of the sequential data to each other,
这些权重定义了序列数据的组成部分之间的关系，
so, for example, in this example with a text sentence,
例如，在这个带有文本句子的例子中，
he tossed the tennis ball to serve,
他抛出了网球发球，
the goal with the score is that
得分的目标是，
words in the sequence that are related to each other should have high attention weights,
序列中相互关联的单词应该具有较高的关注度，
ball related to toss, related to tennis.
球与掷球相关，与网球相关。
And this metric itself is our attention waiting,
这一指标本身就是我们正在等待的关注，
what we have done is passed that similarity score through a softmax function,
我们所做的是通过 softmax 函数传递相似性分数，
which all it does is,
它所做的就是，
it constrains those values to be between zero and one,
将这些值限制在 0 到 1 之间，
and so you can think of these as relative scores of relative attention weights.
因此你可以将这些值视为相对关注度的相对分数。
Finally, now that we have this metric,
最后，现在我们有了这个指标，
that can captures this notion of similarity and these internal self relationships,
它可以捕捉到这种相似性的概念和这些内在的自我关系，
we can finally use this metric to extract features that are deserving of high attention,
我们终于可以使用这个度量来提取值得高度关注的特征，
and that's the exact final step in the self attention mechanism.
这正是自我注意力机制的最后一步。
In that, we take that attention weighting matrix,
在这种情况下，我们采用关注度加权矩阵，
multiply it by the value
将其乘以该值，
and get a transformed transformation of of the initial data
得到的原始数据的变换，
as our output,
作为我们的输出，
which in turn reflects the features that correspond to high attention.
这反过来又反映了与高度关注相对应的特征。
All right, let's take a breath,
好的，让我们深呼吸，
Let's recap what we have just covered so far.
让我们回顾一下我们到目前为止所讨论的内容。
The goal with this idea of self attention, the backbone of transformers,
自我注意力的想法是转换器的支柱，
is to eliminate recurrence,
目标是消除递归，
attend to the most important features in the input data.
注意输入数据中最重要的特征。
In an architecture, how this is actually deployed is,
在架构中，它的实际部署方式是，
first we take our input data,
首先获取我们的输入数据，
we compute these positional encodings,
然后计算这些位置编码，
the neural network layers are applied threefold
神经网络层被三次应用，
to transform the positional encoding into each of the key query and value matrices,
以将位置编码转换为每个键查询和值矩阵，
we can then compute the self attention weight score
然后，我们可以计算自我注意力权重分数，
according to the dot product operation that we went through prior
根据之前进行的点积操作，
and then self attend to these features to these information,
然后对这些特征，对这些信息进行自我关注，
to extract features that deserve high attention,
提取值得高度关注的特征，
what is so powerful about this approach,
这种方法有什么强大的作用，
in taking this attention weight,
在获取注意力权重方面，
putting it together with the value to extract high attention features,
把它和提取高注意力特征的价值放在一起，
is that this operation, the scheme that I'm showing on the right,
这个操作，我在右边展示的方案，
defines a single self attention head
定义了一个单独的自我注意头部，
and multiple of these self attention heads can be linked together
多个这些自我注意力头部可以链接在一起，
to form larger network architectures,
形成更大的网络架构，
where you can think about these different heads,
你可以思考这些不同的头部，
trying to extract different information,
试图提取不同的信息，
different relevant parts of the input,
输入的不同相关部分，
to now put together a very, very rich encoding and representation of the data that we're working with,
现在把我们正在处理的数据的非常非常丰富的编码和表示放在一起，
intuitively back to our iron man example,
直观地回到我们的钢铁侠例子，
what this idea of multiple self attention heads
这种多个自我注意头部的想法，
can amount to is that different salient features and salient information in the data is extracted,
可能相当于提取数据中不同的显著特征和显著信息，
first, maybe you consider iron man attention head one,
首先，也许你认为钢铁侠的注意力一，
and you may have additional attention heads
你可能有额外的注意力头，
that are picking out other relevant parts of the data,
他们正在挑选数据的其他相关部分，
which maybe we did not realize before,
这可能是我们之前没有意识到的，
for example, the building or the spaceship in the background that's chasing iron man,
例如，建筑或背景中正在追逐钢铁侠的宇宙飞船，
and so this is a key building block of many, many, many, many powerful architectures that are out there today,
因此，这是当今许多功能强大的架构的关键组成部分，
today, I again cannot emphasize how enough, how powerful this mechanism is.
我再一次无法强调这一机制是多么多么强大。
And indeed, this backbone idea of self attention
事实上，自我注意的主干概念，
that you just built up understanding of is
你刚刚建立起来的是，
the key operation of some of the most powerful neural networks and deep learning models out there today,
当今一些最强大的神经网络和深度学习模型的关键操作，
ranging from the very powerful language models like GPT 3,
从像 GPT 3 这样非常强大的语言模型，
which are capable of synthesizing natural language in a very human like fashion,
它能够以非常人性化的方式合成自然语言，
digesting large bodies of text information to understand relationships and text,
消化大量的文本信息来理解关系和文本，
to models that are being deployed for extremely impactful applications in biology and medicine,
到在生物学和医学中部署的极具影响力的应用程序的模型，
such as AlphaFold2, which uses this notion of self attention to look at data of protein sequences
例如 AlphaFold2 ，它使用自我注意力的概念来查看蛋白质序列的数据，
and be able to predict the three dimensional structure of a protein
并能够预测蛋白质的三维结构，
just given sequence information alone
只需给定序列信息，
and all the way even now to computer vision,
甚至一直到计算机视觉，
which will be the topic of our next lecture tomorrow,
这将是我们明天下一节课的主题，
where the same idea of attention that was initially developed in sequential data applications
在那里，最初在顺序数据应用程序中开发的相同的注意力概念
has now transformed the field of computer vision
现在已经改变了计算机视觉领域，
and again using this key concept of attending to the important features in an input
并再次使用关注输入中重要特征的关键概念
to build these very rich representations of complex high dimensional data.
来构建复杂高维数据的这些非常丰富的表示形式。
Okay, so that concludes lectures for today,
好的，今天的课程到此结束，
I know we have covered a lot of territory in a pretty short amount of time,
我知道我们在相当短的时间内覆盖了很多领域，
but that is what this boot camp program is all about,
但这就是这个新兵训练营计划的全部意义所在，
so hopefully today you've gotten a sense of the foundations of neural networks,
所以希望今天你已经对神经网络的基础有了一个了解，
in the lecture with Alexander,
在 Alexander 的讲座中，
we talked about RNNs,
我们讨论了 RNN ，
how they're well suited for sequential data,
它们如何很好地适应序列数据，
how we can train them using back propagation,
以及我们如何使用反向传播来训练它们，
how we can deploy them for different applications,
我们如何将它们部署到不同的应用程序中，
and finally, how we can move beyond recurrence
最后，我们如何超越递归，
to build this idea of self attention
以构建自我注意力的概念，
for building increasingly powerful models
以构建越来越强大的模型，
for deep learning in sequence modeling.
以便在序列建模中进行深度学习。
All right, hopefully you enjoyed,
好的，希望你喜欢，
we have about 45 minutes left,
我们还有大约 45 分钟，
for the, for the lab portion and open office hours,
用于实验部分和开放办公时间，
in which we welcome you to ask us questions of us and the TAs
我们欢迎你向我们和助教提问，
and to start work on the labs,
并开始实验，
the information for the labs is up there,
实验的信息就在上面，
thank you so much for your attention.
非常感谢你的关注。